After numerous videos on run time organization and stack machines, we are
在大量关于运行时组织和堆栈机器的视频之后，我们
finally ready to begin our discussion of code generation. So as I mentioned in the
最后，准备开始我们关于代码生成的讨论。所以正如我在
previous video we're going to focus on generating code for stack machines. This
在之前的视频中，我们将重点介绍如何为堆叠机生成代码。这
is probably the simplest code generation strategy. It doesn't generally yield
可能是最简单的代码生成策略。它通常不会屈服
extremely efficient code. It's an interesting strategy and certainly not,
极其高效的代码。这是一个有趣的策略，当然也不是，
totally not an unrealistic one. It's more than complex enough for our purposes. We
完全不是不切实际的。对于我们的目的来说，这已经够复杂的了。我们
want to run a real machine and we're going to the mix processor. In particular we're
想要运行一台真正的机器，我们将使用Mix处理器。尤其是我们正在
going to use a simulator from it which runs on about any kind of hardware so that
我将使用它的模拟器，它可以在任何类型的硬件上运行，因此
will be very convenient for the course project And the basic idea, the basic
将会很方便的介绍课程项目和基本思路、基本
strategy, is going to be to simulate a stack machine using Mipp's instructions
策略将是使用MIPP的指令模拟堆叠机
and registers. So the first decision in, designing our simulation, is deciding
和寄存器。因此，在设计我们的模拟时，第一个决策是决定
where to put the accumulator in. We'll keep that, in this register, A0. Any
把蓄电池放在哪里。我们会把它保存在这个寄存器里，A0。任何
register would have done but we'll just use A0 always for the accumulator And then
寄存器本来可以这样做，但我们将始终使用A0作为累加器，然后
the stack is going to be kept in memory And I should point out here that when we
堆栈将保存在内存中，我应该在此指出，当我们
talk about a one register stack machine nominally that register in this case A0,
在这种情况下，谈论名义上寄存器为A0单寄存器堆栈机，
is the top of the logical stack of the stack machine But just to avoid confusion
是堆栈机器逻辑堆栈的顶部，但只是为了避免念力
in the terminology, I'm going to refer to A0 as the accumulator and the stack as all
在术语中，我将A0称为累加器，将堆栈称为All
of the other data that's kept in a memory stack on the MISC processor, so we'll just
保存在MISC处理器的内存堆栈中的其他数据，所以我们只需
consider A0 the accumulator to be distinct from the stack, which lives in memory And
考虑A0累加器与堆栈不同，堆栈驻留在内存中，
the stack on the MIPS will grow towards the lower addresses which is the standard
MIPS上的堆栈将向更低的地址增长，这是标准
convention on MIPS. The address of the next location on the stack is going to be
关于MIPS的约定。堆栈上下一个位置的地址将是
kept in the MIPS register $sp and this register actually has a mnemonic name that
保存在MIPS寄存器$sp中，该寄存器实际上有一个助记符名称，该名称
stand for stack pointer. So, normally on the MIPS machine, compilers use SP to,
代表堆栈指针。因此，通常在MIPS机器上，编译器使用SP来
point to, their stack, and the top of the stack will always be at the address, SP
指向它们的堆栈，堆栈的顶部将始终位于地址SP
plus four. So, remember the stack is growing towards low addresses, and the
加四个。因此，请记住堆栈正在向低位地址增长，并且
address, in the stack pointer is the ne xt unallocated location on the stack. So the
堆栈指针中的地址是堆栈上的next未分配位置。因此，
stack pointer actually points to unused memory, and the top of the stack,
堆栈指针实际上指向未使用的内存，堆栈的顶部
therefore, is at the next higher word address which would be SP plus four, Now
因此，现在位于下一个较高的字地址，即SP加4
the MIPS architecture is quite an old architecture. It was designed in the
MIPS架构是一个相当古老的架构。它是在
1980's and it was, or is, the prototypical reduced instruction set computer, or risk
20世纪80年代，它曾经是，或者现在是典型的精简指令集计算机，或称Risk
machine. And the idea behind RISC machines was to have a relatively simple
机器。RISC机器背后的想法是拥有一个相对简单的
instruction set. Most of the operations used registers for operands and results.
指令集。大多数操作使用寄存器来存储操作数和结果。
And then load and store instructions are used to move values to and from memory. So
然后使用加载和存储指令将值移入和移出存储器。所以
primarily all the computation takes place in registers, and the memory operations
首先，所有的计算都在寄存器中进行，而内存操作
are primarily are just loading and storing data. There are 32 purp-, there are 32
主要是加载和存储数据。有32个紫色的，有32个的
general-purpose registers on the MITS, it's a 32 bit machine. We're only going to
MITS上的通用寄存器，它是一台32位机器。我们只打算
use three of those registers. We already talked about SP, the stack pointer. A0 the
使用其中的三个寄存器。我们已经讨论了堆栈指针SP。A0 The
accumulator, and we'll need one more register for temporary values. So some
累加器，我们还需要一个寄存器来存放临时值。所以有些人
operations that take two arguments like plus and times will have to have two
接受两个参数(如加号和时间)的运算必须有两个
registers to hold the arguments to the operation. So we'll use the accumulator
寄存器以保存操作的参数。所以我们将使用累加器
for one of those and a temporary register for the other. And there is a lot more
其中一个是临时登记簿，另一个是临时登记簿。而且还有更多的东西
information on the MIPS architecture in the SPIM documentation. Spim is the
SPIM文档中有关MIPS体系结构的信息。SPIM是
simulator that we, we'll use to execute MIPS code. Now of course, to, generate
我们，我们要用来执行MIPS代码的模拟器。现在当然是为了，产生
code for the mix. We'll also need some mix instructions. And we'll be able to get
混合的代码。我们还需要一些配料说明。我们就能得到
away, with just a very small number of instructions. Five in fact, for our first
离开了，只有很少的指令。实际上是五个，这是我们第一次
example And here they are. So the first instruction we need, is load, or load word
例如，它们就在这里。因此，我们需要的第一条指令是LOAD或LOAD WORD
And the way this works is it takes the value of register two, takes the contents
它的工作方式是取寄存器2的值，取内容
that are in register two Adds a fixed offset. So this is a number that's,
寄存器2中的寄存器添加固定偏移量。所以这是一个数字，
directly in the code Adds a fixed offset to that to the contents of register two.
直接在代码中将固定偏移量添加到寄存器2的内容中。
That's a memory address. It loads the value of that memory address into register
那是一个内存地址。它将该内存地址的值加载到寄存器中
one. The add instruction adds the contents of register two and register three
一。ADD指令将寄存器2和寄存器3的内容相加
together and stores the results in register one again. The store operation,
并再次将结果存储在寄存器1中。存储操作，
or store word operation takes the value in register one and stores it into memory. So
或存储字操作获取寄存器1中的值并将其存储到存储器中。所以
that's stored at a memory address, and with the memory address is the contents of
它存储在内存地址中，与内存地址一起的是
register two, plus a fixed offset that's in the code. And an add immediate
寄存器2，加上代码中的固定偏移量。和添加立即
unsigned, takes, is an unsigned add, and it takes a value in register two, an
UNSIGNED，Take，是一个无符号加法，它接受寄存器2中的一个值，一个
immediate value. So, this is just a number, that's a constant that's directly
立即值。所以，这只是一个数字，这是一个常数，它直接
embedded in the code. It adds that to the value register two and stores the result
嵌入到代码中。它将其加到值寄存器2并存储结果
in register one. And the unsigned aspect here just means that the overflow is not
在第一收银台。而这里的无符号方面只是意味着溢出不是
checked, we're not, we're not checking whether we generate a number that's
检查过了，我们没有，我们没有检查我们是否生成了一个
beyond, beyond what we could represent if we had sine numbers. Finally, load
超出了，超出了如果我们有正弦数的话我们可以表示的范围。最后，加载
immediate just takes a constant that's in the code, and puts it into, the register
IMMEDIATE只是接受代码中的常量，并将其放入寄存器
that's named as the first argument Alright? So those are the five
这被命名为第一个论点，好吗？那么这五个就是
instructions that we need, to do a, one very simple example. So now we're ready to
我们需要的指令，来做一个，一个非常简单的例子。所以现在我们准备好
do our first program, and not surprisingly it's the same program that we looked at in
做我们的第一个程序，不出所料，它和我们在
previous videos when we were talking about stack machine code. So let's look, here's
以前我们讨论堆栈机器代码时的视频。我们来看看，这是
the program for adding seven plus five, written out in our little abstract stack
7加5的程序，写在我们的小抽象堆栈中
machine language. Now our goal is to implement this program using MIPS
机器语言。现在我们的目标是使用MIPS实现此计划
instructions. So over here on the right, I'm going to layout the instructions we
说明书。在这里，在右边，我将布局我们的指令
would use to simulate this program or implement this program on the MIPS machine
将用于在MIPS计算机上模拟此程序或实现此程序
Alright? So the first instruction is to load seven into the accumulator. And we
好吗？因此，第一条指令是将7加载到累加器中。而我们
can do that with a load immediate. We're going to load immediate the value seven.
可以立即装货做到这一点。我们要立即加载价值7。
A0 is our accumulator register, and so this instruction puts seven in the
A0是我们的累加器寄存器，因此此指令将7放入
accumulator. Next instruction, we want to push the value of the accumulator onto the
累加器。下一条指令中，我们希望将累加器的值压入
stack. How do we do that? Well we have to store the value onto the stack, and
堆栈。我们该怎么做呢？我们必须将值存储到堆栈中，并且
remember the stack pointer points to the next unused memory location. And so we're
记住，堆栈指针指向下一个未使用的内存位置。所以我们要
just storing directly at what the stack pointer points to, so that's at zero
直接存储在堆栈指针指向的位置，所以它是零
offset from the stack pointer. The value of the accumulator pushes the value onto
堆栈指针的偏移量。累加器的值会将该值推送到
the stack, and now to restore the invariant. That the stack pointer points
堆栈，现在恢复不变量。堆栈指针指向的
to the next unused location, we have to subtract four from the stack pointer.
到下一个未使用的位置，我们必须从堆栈指针中减去4。
Okay. So, these two instructions together, implement a push, they push the data value
好吧。因此，这两条指令一起实现推送，它们推送数据值
onto the stack, and they move the stack pointer to the next unused address.
放到堆栈上，然后它们将堆栈指针移动到下一个未使用的地址。
Alright, now I'm ready to do the next instruction, loading five into the
好的，现在我准备好执行下一条指令，将五个加载到
accumulator. Well, we already know how to do that. We'll be a load immediate into
累加器。嗯，我们已经知道怎么做了。我们马上就会满载而归
the accumulator register A0, the immediate value five Are now ready to do the add And
累加器寄存器A0、立即值5现在准备好进行加法和
how does that work? Well, first, we have to load the value of that's on the top of
那是怎么回事呢？好的，首先，我们要把它的值加载到
the stack, alright. Because it's like an argument is taken from the top of the
堆栈，好的。因为这就像是从
stack. And since MIPS can only do operations out of registers, that value
堆栈。由于MIPS只能在寄存器之外执行操作，因此该值
has to go somewhere into a register. And this is where we use our temporary
一定要放到收银机的某个地方。这就是我们用我们的临时
register. So now, this value is now at offset four from the stack pointer,
注册。所以现在，这个值现在位于堆栈指针的偏移量4处，
because we subtracted four from the stack pointer And we load it into register T1.
因为我们从堆栈指针中减去4，然后将其加载到寄存器T1中。
Okay, And then we can actually perform the add. And so we add the accumulator to the
好的，然后我们就可以进行加法了。因此我们将累加器添加到
value of T1 and we store the result back into the accumulator And finally we're
值，我们将结果存储回累加器中，最后我们
going to pop the stack so we're done with the value that's on the stack, And how do
我要弹出堆栈，这样我们就完成了堆栈上的值，该如何做
we pop? Well, we just add four to the stack pointer, and that moves the stack
我们突击吗？嗯，我们只需将4加到堆栈指针上，这就移动了堆栈
pointer back popping that value off of the stack.
将该值从堆栈中弹出的指针。